cwidaho.cc 2017-12-26

# Privacy Statement | College of Western Idaho

### Cwidaho.cc's Commitment to Privacy

Thank you for visiting the College of Western Idaho (CWI) website and reviewing our Online Privacy Statement. The College of Western Idaho is committed to protecting your privacy and making it easier and more efficient for individuals and businesses to interact with CWI. We recognize that it is critical for individuals and businesses to be confident that their privacy is protected when they visit cwidaho.cc. You can travel through most of this website without providing any information about yourself. On occasion we do request information to provide services that you request, and this commitment of privacy explains our online information practices.

CWI does not collect any _personal informatio_ n about you unless you provide that information voluntarily by sending e-mail, completing an online information request form, completing the online application, or completing online registration.

This policy is consistent with the provisions of the Internet Security and Privacy Act, the Freedom of Information Law, and the Personal Privacy Protection Law.

### Information Collected Automatically When You Visit cwidaho.cc

When visiting cwidaho.cc, CWI automatically collects and stores the following information about your visit:

  * The Internet Protocol address and Internet Service Provider of the computer that accessed our website
  * The type of browser, its version and the operating system on which that browser is running
  * The Web page from which the user accessed the current Web page
  * The date and time of the _user's_ request
  * The pages that were visited and the amount of time spent at each page

None of the above-mentioned information is deemed to constitute _personal information_ by the Internet Privacy and Security Act. The information that is collected automatically is used to improve cwidaho.cc's content and to help CWI understand how _users_ are interacting with its website. This information is collected for statistical analysis and to determine what information is of most and least interest to our _users_. The information is not collected for commercial marketing purposes and CWI is not authorized to sell or otherwise disclose the information collected from cwidaho.cc for commercial marketing purposes.

### Information Collected When You E-mail cwidaho.cc or Complete a Transaction

During your visit to cwidaho.cc you may send an e-mail to CWI. Your e-mail address and the contents of your message will be collected. The information collected is not limited to text characters and may include audio, video, and graphic information formats included in the message. Your e-mail address and the information included in your message will be used to respond to you, to address issues you identify, to improve this website, or to forward your message to another CWI department for appropriate action. Your e-mail address is not collected for commercial purposes and CWI is not authorized to sell or otherwise disclose your e-mail address for commercial purposes.

During your visit to cwidaho.cc you may complete a transaction such as an online application contribution, survey, or an online information request form. The information collected by CWI, including _personal information_ volunteered by you in completing the transaction, is used by CWI and may be disclosed by CWI for those purposes that may be reasonably ascertained from the nature and terms of the transaction in which the information was submitted.

CWI does not knowingly collect _personal information_ from children under the age of 13 or create profiles of children under the age of 13. Users are cautioned, however, that the collection of _personal information_ submitted in an e-mail will be treated as though it was submitted by an adult, and may, unless exempted from access by federal or state law, be subject to public access.

### Disclosure of Information Collected 

The collection of information through cwidaho.cc and the disclosure of that information are subject to the provisions of the Internet Security and Privacy Act. CWI will only collect _personal information_ through cwidaho.cc or disclose _personal information_ collected through cwidaho.cc if the user has consented to the collection or disclosure of such _personal information_. The voluntary disclosure of _personal information_ to CWI by the user, constitutes consent to the collection and disclosure of the information by CWI for the purposes for which the user disclosed the information to CWI.

However, CWI may collect or disclose _personal information_ without consent if the collection or disclosure is: (1) necessary to perform the statutory duties of CWI, or necessary for CWI to operate a program authorized by law, or authorized by state or federal statute or regulation; (2) made pursuant to a court order or by law; (3) for the purpose of validating the identity of the user; or (4) of information to be used solely for statistical purposes that is in a form that cannot be used to identify any particular person.

If personal information is requested on the website or volunteered by the user, state law and the [federal Privacy Act of 1974](http://www.justice.gov/opcl/1974privacyact-overview.htm) may protect it. However, some of the information may become public record once you provide it and may be subject to public inspection and copying if not protected by federal or state law.

Further, the disclosure of information, including _personal information_ , collected through cwidaho.cc is subject to the provisions of the Freedom of Information Law and the Personal Privacy Protection Law.

CWI may disclose _personal information_ to federal or state law enforcement authorities to enforce its rights against unauthorized access or attempted unauthorized access to CWI’s information technology assets.

### Retention of Information Collected

The information collected through cwidaho.cc is retained by CWI in accordance with the records retention and disposition requirements of the Idaho State Law. In the state of Idaho, laws exist to ensure that government is open and the public has a right to access appropriate records and information possessed by state government. At the same time, there are exceptions to the public's right to access public records that serve various needs, including the privacy of individuals. Exceptions are provided by both state and federal laws. In general, the Internet services logs of CWI, comprising electronic files or automated logs created to monitor access and use of College services provided through cwidaho.cc, are archived for future reference. Information concerning these records retention and disposition schedules may be obtained the CWI Policy Manual.

### _Personal Information_ and Choice

You may choose whether to provide personal information online.

Personal information is information about a natural person that is readily identifiable to that specific individual. Personal information includes such things as an individual's name, address, and phone number. A domain name or Internet Protocol address is not considered personal information.

We collect no personal information about you unless you voluntarily provide it to us by sending us e-mail, participating in a survey, or completing an on-line form. You may choose not to contact us by e-mail, participate in a survey or to provide any personal information using an online form. Your choice to not participate in these activities will not impair your ability to browse the CWI website and read or download any information provided on the site. The college information telephone can be found on the footer of every page. Directories list telephone numbers of every department and service on campus.

If personal information is requested on the Web site or volunteered by the user, state law and the federal Privacy Act of 1974 may protect it. However, this information is a public record once you provide it, and may be subject to public inspection and copying if not protected by federal or state law.

If you believe that your personal information is being used for a purpose other than what was intended when submitted, you may contact the communications department as shown in the Contact Information section of this statement.

### Confidentiality and Integrity of _Personal Information_ Collected Through cwidaho.cc

CWI is strongly committed to protecting _personal information_ collected through cwidaho.cc against unauthorized access, use or disclosure. Consequently, CWI limits employee access to _personal information_ collected through cwidaho.cc to only those employees who need access to the information in the performance of their official duties. Employees who have access to this information follow appropriate procedures in connection with any disclosures of _personal information_.

In addition, CWI has implemented procedures to safeguard the integrity of its information technology assets, including, but not limited to, authentication, authorization, monitoring, auditing, and encryption. These security procedures have been integrated into the design, implementation, and day-to-day operations of cwidaho.cc as part of our continuing commitment to the security of electronic content as well as the electronic transmission of information.

For website security purposes and to maintain the availability of cwidaho.cc for all _users_ , CWI employs software to monitor traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information or otherwise damage cwidaho.cc.

### Cookies and Applets

Cookies are simple text files stored on your web browser to provide a means of distinguishing among users of this website. The use of cookies is a standard practice among Internet websites. To better serve you, we may use "session cookies" to enhance or customize your visit to this website. Session cookies, which can be created automatically on the device you use to access this state agency website, do not contain personal information and do not compromise your privacy or security. We may use the cookie feature to store a randomly generated identifying tag on the device you use to access this website. A session cookie is erased during operation of your browser or when your browser is closed. The software and hardware you use to access the website allows you to refuse new cookies or delete existing cookies.

Applets are tools downloaded to your computer to work with the software you have. Applets are intended to enhance your browsing experience by enabling you to view information in a unique manner or enable access to information that your computer would otherwise be unable to access without the applet.

Refusing or deleting these cookies and applets may limit your ability to take advantage of some features of this website.

### Disclaimer

The policies and practices described in this disclosure are subject to change, but we will promptly post any significant changes online for your information.

Please note that CWI is not responsible for the content or privacy practices of non-CWI websites to which this site or any other CWI website may link. You should review the privacy policy of such sites before using the sites.

This information should not be construed in any way as giving business, legal, or other advice, or warranting as fail proof, the security of information provided via College of Western Idaho websites.

## Need more info?

For questions regarding this Internet privacy statement, please contact our communications department:

**(via e-mail)**  
[[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#e88b8785859d86818b899c8187869ba88b9f818c898087c68b8b)

**(via regular mail)**  
Communications  
College of Western Idaho  
MS 1000  
P.O. Box 3010  
Nampa, ID 83653

**Student related requests:**  
CWI Registrar at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#651700020c16111704172506120c01040d0a4b0606)
